<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.calstfrancis.kopilka</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>

  <name>Kopilka</name>
  <summary>Couples budget planner with shared finance management</summary>

  <description>
    <p>
      Kopilka is a GTK4 budget planner for two-person households. Track income,
      fixed expenses, debt, discretionary spending, assets, and savings goals in
      a shared JSON file that can be synced via pCloud or any shared folder.
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>Dashboard with income breakdown, net budget, bills calendar, net worth, and category spending bars</li>
      <li>Income tracking for multiple sources per person</li>
      <li>Fixed expenses with calendar view and next-due dates</li>
      <li>Debt management with payoff projections and what-if extra payment slider</li>
      <li>Discretionary spending with per-category budgets, rollover, and seasonal overrides</li>
      <li>One-time purchase pool for irregular expenses</li>
      <li>Recurring entries that auto-insert into the spending log</li>
      <li>Spending log grouped by date with category tagging</li>
      <li>Reports with donut charts, monthly bar charts, and per-category trends</li>
      <li>Asset accounts with balance history and savings goal tracker</li>
      <li>Sync via pCloud — detects external file changes on window focus and offers a one-click reload</li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.calstfrancis.kopilka.desktop</launchable>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/calstfrancis/kopilka/main/screenshots/kopilka-main.png</image>
      <caption>Dashboard showing income, budget breakdown, and upcoming bills</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/calstfrancis/kopilka</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/calstfrancis/kopilka/issues</url>

  <developer>
    <name>Cal St Francis</name>
  </developer>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>

  <releases>
    <release version="0.5.5" date="2026-06-20">
      <description>
        <p>"Level Ledger" — math corrections, crash fixes, and UX clarity improvements.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Annual one-time purchase pool now correctly uses unallocated discretionary funds, not the full pre-category discretionary amount.</li>
          <li>Debt avalanche and snowball strategies now model payment cascade — freed payments from a paid-off debt roll into the next priority debt.</li>
          <li>Recurring entries no longer risk crashing the app at startup; processing is now owned by the main window after all views are initialised, and also fires when the window regains focus.</li>
          <li>Budget saves are now atomic (temp-file + rename) — a crash during write can no longer corrupt budget.json.</li>
          <li>Category color pills with light backgrounds (yellow, stone) now use black text for legibility.</li>
          <li>CSV export from the spending log now respects the active time filter instead of always exporting full history.</li>
          <li>One-time date fields in income and expense forms now validate the ISO date before saving.</li>
          <li>Monthly Reports summary now applies seasonal budget overrides for the current month.</li>
          <li>Monthly trend bars now show category spending only; fixed one-time expenses are annotated separately.</li>
          <li>Dashboard category rows now display the time window (e.g. "week of 16 Jun") so mixed weekly/monthly rows are unambiguous.</li>
          <li>Bill reminders now show billing frequency in the subtitle and per-period unit on the amount.</li>
          <li>Income rows now display the per-period unit (e.g. $3,500/2wk).</li>
          <li>Income amount field now prompts to enter take-home (after-tax) pay.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.5.4" date="2026-06-10">
      <description>
        <p>Bug fixes: calculations, data integrity, and feedback.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Biweekly income and expense amounts now use the correct monthly conversion factor (26/12 instead of 2.165).</li>
          <li>Recurring entries with a past next_date no longer freeze the app on open.</li>
          <li>Monthly budget category overrides are no longer silently lost when the budget file is reloaded.</li>
          <li>A toast is shown if the budget file cannot be saved (disk full, permissions error).</li>
          <li>Deleting a category now shows how many spending entries will become "Unknown category".</li>
          <li>Version number in the status bar and About dialog is now consistent.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.5.3" date="2026-06-10">
      <description>
        <p>Launch reliability fix.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>App now opens correctly from the GNOME launcher and Discover — repeated launches raise the existing window instead of failing silently.</li>
          <li>Fixed a GTK markup warning caused by a bare ampersand in the "Savings &amp; Investments" dashboard label.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.5.2" date="2026-06-09">
      <description>
        <p>Status bar with toggles and about dialog.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>New status bar at the bottom of the window with SIMPLE and GOST toggle buttons — replaces the sidebar switches.</li>
          <li>Active toggles appear bold; inactive toggles are dimmed — consistent with Rubric and Zerkalo.</li>
          <li>Version chip on the right opens the GNOME About dialog with release notes.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.5.1" date="2026-06-09">
      <description>
        <p>Critical fix: app now opens correctly on all Linux distributions.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Flatpak was built against GNOME Platform 50, which is not yet available on most systems — downgraded to Platform 48.</li>
          <li>Desktop file missing StartupWMClass — launcher icon and window now group correctly in the taskbar.</li>
          <li>Settings view showed stale partner names and bills look-ahead after a budget reload.</li>
          <li>Budget open/create errors now show a toast instead of silently failing.</li>
          <li>Recurring entry insertion no longer causes the spending log to render twice.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.5.0" date="2026-06-06">
      <description>
        <p>Delete confirmation dialogs, Today button on all date fields, friendly date headers in spending log, budget load error notification, and several bug fixes.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
